Inventory of the Hugo Butler Papers, 1937-1971
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Hugo Butler papers
1937-1971
Butler, Hugo, 1914-1968
03208
6.00 cubic ft. (8 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Screenplays and associated materials of this Hollywood motion picture writer.
Biography of Hugo Butler
Hugo Butler began writing for the movies in Hollywood in 1937. He wrote screenplays for Huckleberry Finn (1939), Lassie Come Home (1943), and Robinson Crusoe (1954). He was nominated for an Academy Award for Edison the Man (1940). In 1951 Butler and his wife, Jean Rouverol, moved to Mexico as a result of blacklisting in Hollywood. Butler wrote documentary screenplays and worked with film director Luis Buñuel while in Mexico. For a time he lived in Italy to work on The Last Days of Sodom and Gomorrah. In 1964 the family returned to California. Butler and Jean Rouverol were working together on the screenplay of The Legend of Lilah Clare when Butler died in 1968.
Scope and Content
The Hugo Butler papers contain screenplays, reviews, and some publicity and production notes for motion pictures authored by Hugo Butler.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Hugo Butler at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Jean Rouverol Butler in 1969 and 1978.
Access Terms
Rouverol, Jean;; Motion picture authorship; Motion pictures; Screenwriters;;; Scripts;; Sodom and Gomorrah (Motion picture); Legend of Lylah Clare (Motion picture); Robinson Crusoe (Motion picture); Toreror (Motion picture); Eva (Motion picture)
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts; Social Life and Customs; People, Ethnicity, and Culture
Container List
- Contracts, Professional Correspondence, Publicity, 1938-circa 1965 (Box 7)
- Eva: scripts, production materials, reviews, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
- Legend of Lylah Clare: scripts, production materials, 1967-1968 (Box 6-7)
- Little Giants (Los Pequeños Gigantes): scripts, production materials, reviews, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
- Reviews: Big City; Christmas Carol; Edison the Man; Face in the Rain; First Time; Huckleberry Finn; Lassie Come Home; Society Lawyer; Wyoming, 1937-1963 (Box 7)
- Robinson Crusoe: scripts, production materials, reviews, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
- Sodom and Gomorrah: scripts, production materials, reviews, 1960-1961 (Box 1-4)
- Toreror: scripts, production materials, reviews, 1955-1956 (Box 8)
- Various Motion Picture Scripts by Hugo Butler, 1937-1971 (Box 5, 7)
- The Young One: script, reviews, 1959-1960 (Box 8)